Finding aid to the Jean S. Wilson Papers CA.MS.00404
Smith College Archives
Jean S. Wilson Papers
1924-1993
Smith College Archives
Wilson, Jean S.
CA.MS.00404
0.208 linear feet (1 container)
Contains correspondence, brochures, photographs, and news clippings from the papers of Jean S. Wilson, Professor of History 1927-1968.
Biographical / Historical
Jean S. Wilson was born in Duluth, Minnesota, in 1903 to Alexander Strachan and Agnes (Gibson) Wilson. She received her B.A. from Smith College in 1924 and then received her Ph.D. from the University of London in 1927. Wilson came to Smith as a member of the History faculty in the same year. Wilson's research centered largely on early seventeenth century English history, especially people's attitudes toward government reform in the era. In 1930, she won the Social Science Research Fellowship to return to the University of London for research. While at Smith, Wilson was a member of Phi Beta Kappa, the American Historical Association, the British Records Association, and the Conference on British Studies Committee. Wilson also taught as a traveling professor to Swarthmore College and to the University of Iowa. She was named the Sydenham Clark Parsons professor of History in 1963. She retired in 1968, living in Northampton until her death in 1993.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the professional papers of Jean S. Wilson, including correspondence with students, professional photographs, and news clippings about her career. The collection also contains the papers of the Service Organization of Smith (SOS), which include budgets of the organization, correspondence and brochures from the organization they donated to, and internal correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students.
In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Wilson, Jean S.
- Professor of History, 1927-1958, 1927-1993 (Box 1085.1, Folder 1)
- Letters from students, undated (Box 1085.1, Folder 2)
- Letters from students, 1941-1957 (Box 1085.1, Folder 3)
- Letters from students, 1958-1963 (Box 1085.1, Folder 4)
- Letters from students, 1964-1965 (Box 1085.1, Folder 5)
- Letters from students, 1966-1970 (Box 1085.1, Folder 6)
- Letters from students, 1971-1985 (Box 1085.1, Folder 7)
- Letters from students: RESTRICTED (Box 1085.1, Folder 8)
- S.O.S.: Danilo Dolci, 1964-1965 (Box 1085.1, Folder 9)
- S.O.S.: Greece, 1924-1964 (Box 1085.1, Folder 10)
- S.O.S.: Mississippi, 1964-1965 (Box 1085.1, Folder 11)
- S.O.S.: Miscellaneous including Ginling, 1958 (Box 1085.1, Folder 12)
- Unitarian: Toulouse, 1958-1965 (Box 1085.1, Folder 13)